Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/tara-scanlonb199a6a (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Media Planning Media Strategy Advertising

Tara Scanlon

VP, Strategy at dentsu X (previously 360i)
Greater Boston

Summary

What Drives Me: Emotionally intelligent leadership. Complex, consumer-driven business challenges. Teamwork. Data. Common sense strategy. Socially responsible marketing. B-Corps. All things "first to market". Equity. TikTok voyeurism. Making my cat proud.

Industry Vertical Experience: CPG (Food, Home, Health & Hygiene), Travel, Spirits, E-Comm, Technology, Retail. Local, National and International Planning. Fluent in all media. Passion for rigorous Brand Strategy, Communications Planning and campaign ecosystems that just. make. sense.

Experience

dentsu X

4 years 1 month

VP, Strategy

June 2022 - Present (2 years 9 months)

VP, Planning

February 2021 - June 2022 (1 year 5 months)

- -- Lead integrated communication planning and buying across North American business units for CPG, & Travel based clients including Creative + Media services
- -- Oversee cross-functional media team focused on driving brand & performance focused media plans
- -- Clients: Ben & Jerry's, Amplify Snacks, Vital Farms, New Orleans & Co. Previously on PURELL

360i

5 years 2 months

Group Director, Planning
June 2019 - February 2021 (1 year 9 months)

New York, New York

-- Clients: Pernod Ricard (Whisky & Gin), Ben & Jerry's, Amplify Snacks, Vital Farms, New Orleans & Co, PURELL

Director, Planning

January 2016 - May 2019 (3 years 5 months)

Greater New York City Area

Strategic communications planning across Pernod Ricard Whisky, SkinnyPop and Ben & Jerry's. Previously on RB and Plated

Dentsu Aegis Network

Associate Director, Communications Planning

March 2014 - January 2016 (1 year 11 months)

Strategic communications planning & execution on Reckitt Benckiser

OMD USA

Supervisor

July 2012 - March 2014 (1 year 9 months)

Strategy Supervisor on the Quaker Oats account

- -- Oversee the planning, development and coordinate the execution of integrated media plans across Quaker portfolio of brands
- -- Responsibilities include development of communication strategy, target insights, investment prioritization & market trend analyses

MindShare

2 years 1 month

Manager

January 2011 - July 2012 (1 year 7 months)

Media Manager on LG account - specifically concentrating on the Mobile sector

Senior Associate

July 2010 - January 2011 (7 months)

Planner on the LG Mobile business

OMD USA

2 years 2 months

Media Strategist

July 2009 - July 2010 (1 year 1 month)

Strategist/Planner on Lowe's Home Improvement account

Assistant Strategist

June 2008 - July 2009 (1 year 2 months)
Assistant Strategist on Lowe's Home Improvement account

Education

New York University
BS, Media, Culture and Communications · (2004 - 2008)